musictribe.com 2012-11-03

# Privacy Policy | MusicTribe

This agreement pertains to your access to Musictribe.com; the Music Tribe applications on Facebook, Twitter and other social platforms; Music Tribe widgets designed for embedding on any website; Music Tribe RSS feeds,  and other services (Services and services are collectively the “Services”). Music Tribe believes in the responsible use of personal information. We understand that without the trust and respect of the musicians and fans that make up our community we have nothing. So well strive to honor the privacy of anyone who signs up as a member.

  **Your Personal Information at Music Tribe**  
Music Tribe is the sole owner of the personal information collected on its Services and we collect personal information from our users at several different points on these Services. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this Privacy Policy. Music Tribe ask for personal information only when its necessary in order to deliver value-add service to you. We require certain pieces of information so we can provide you a personalized experience. And while we may use this information for research and to improve the site and services we offer you, except as stated herein or as you specifically give us permission, we promise not to pass on personally identifiable information to third parties.  
Here is the information that we require for basic registration for our Services:  
Display Name is collected and made public on the site. (Your Display Name becomes your public display-name at our Services. It doesn’t need to bear a relation to your actual name). The following information is collected at registration:  
Your email address.  
Your age  
A password for your account. (We remind you not to reveal your password to anyone).  
If you are an artist, your Band Name  
In addition, you are invited to “opt in” to receive a regular newsletter or occasional email from our Services, and you are free to opt out from either of these services at any point in the future.  
You have the option of providing more private information to personalize your experience but are not required to do so.  
Lastly, in general on the Services, you may provide information for your Public Profile to introduce yourself to other members of our Services, including the information listed above, or other information, but are under no obligation to do so.  
If you register your Band or yourself as an Artist with the Services, you may be required to provide us with your first and last names, band members, a short biography, and place of origin. This information will be made public on your bands profile page. In addition you may provide additional information about your band for public display on your Band Profile, but are under no obligation to do so.  
The information that you provide for your Public Profile or for your Band Profile will be publicly displayed without restriction on our Services. By providing such information for public display, you recognize that it may be considered public domain and as such may be viewed, copied, or re-distributed by anybody who uses our Services. This public information includes without limitation your music preferences and any other information you choose to make available such as your own name, others names, images, song names and biographical information. Nevertheless, you retain any trademark rights of your band/song names and any copyright of your music and lyrics.

  **Cookies**  
Be aware that our Services use cookies. Cookies are small packets of information we place on your hard drive for tracking purposes – essentially a code number that we use to recognize you when you come back to the site. Only the information you volunteer, however, or the choices you make while visiting the site, can be stored in a cookie. A cookie cannot determine your email address, for example, unless you type it in. Allowing a website to create a cookie does not give that or any other site access to the rest of your computer, and only the site that created the cookie can read it.  
Our Services also use permanent cookies that store an encrypted session id code. This means we are able to recognize you when you come to the site, without the need for you to log in.   
If your browser is set to reject cookies, you will not be able to log in to the site and hold an account. This means you will not be able to review music, register a band, and so on. You will, however, be able to browse most of the site freely.  
Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site. However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for processing your order.

  **Log Files**  
We log IP addresses to track which users have made what page requests, what browser that person was using, what their cookie was, and at what time the request was made. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the site, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. This logging process does not store any personally identifiable information.

  **Emails**  
Except for administrative emails covering usage of our Services, all other emails we send are under your control. You may register your wishes at the Profile Settings section of Music Tribe.com. We issue many types of email communication. The following is a non-comprehensive list: (1) we send a registration email when you first become a member (2) we send a regular opt-in newsletter (3) we provide an opt-in subscription to occasional emails for the announcement of new site features, special events, etc (4) we send invitations or add friend requests at the request of your friends who are users of our service; we may send one follow up email to such invitations if they do not generate a response the first time (5) we notify you of updates that have happened to your account, your profile page, or your band page (6) if you are in a band, we notify you of changes in your status within a contest, reviews of your music, or latest usage statistics on your uploaded music (7) we may notify you when you receive messages from other members of the service.

  **Sharing**  
We may share general user profile and demographic information with our partners and advertisers, for purposes including, but not limited to, the delivery of targeted advertising. This information will not be linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.  
Though we make reasonable efforts to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on us or one of our Services.

  **Links**  
Our Services contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by our Services.

  **Surveys & Contests**  
From time-to-time our site may request information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name, telephone number and shipping address). Contact information (including telephone number and address) will be used to notify the winners and award prizes and by giving us your phone number you acknowledge and agree that we may contact you by telephone in connection with such survey or contest . Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. We sometimes partner with third parties to implement our surveys and contests. Personally identifiable information may be initially received by and passed on to Music Tribe by such third parties.

  **Partner Sites**  
We have partnered with third parties to enable bands to sell their music and with other partners to provide our community with editorial content (pro advice, celebrity interviews, and so on). At times, while purchasing music or reading articles, you may be viewing pages hosted by one of these or other partners – although it may look as if you are still at one of our Services. To tell where you are, simply check the address of the page in your browsers address window.

  **BETA  Disclaimer**  
Our Services are currently available as a Beta release. While Music Tribe strives to maintain all of the above privacy precautions, our services are not devoid of risk of bugs and software faultiness that is common with Beta software. As is made clear in the Terms of Service regarding, Music Tribe disclaims and limits its liability with respect to such a Beta software, including limitation of its any liability regarding privacy issues set forth in this policy.

  **Conflicts**  
In the event of an inconsistency between these, this Privacy Policy and Music Tribe “Terms of Use,” the Terms of Use shall control.

  **Merger**

  Music Tribe may assign any or all of its rights hereunder and may transfer data collected or acquired hereunder in the event of a merger or acquisition of all or substantially all of the assets of Music Tribe. In the event that Music Tribe, or a portion of its business is acquired, the acquiring party will only acquire your personally identifiable information subject to the terms of this privacy policy.

  More information…  
If you wish to learn more about our privacy policies please contact [info@musictribe.com](mailto:info@musictribe.com)

  If we decide to materially change our privacy policy, we may notify users by way of an email.
